ABHISHEK PRATAP SINGH

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

💌 abhishekssiin@gmail.com 📞 +917011127266 💡 GURGAON | INDIA 🛗 14/10/1996

in linkedin.com/in/abhish1s

Education

B.TECH., INDERPRASTHA ENGINEERING COLLEGE 08/2015 - 06/2019 | Ghaziabad, India 73.60% | Computer Science & Engineering

INTERMEDIATE, ST. FRANCIS INTER COLLEGE 05/2013 - 06/2014 | Hathras, India 64.60% | Science Stream

HIGH SCHOOL, ST. FRANCIS INTER COLLEGE 05/2011 - 04/2012 | Hathras, India 8.0 CGPA | Science Stream

Professional Experience

Software Engineer, *Xoriant Solutions Pvt. Ltd.* 03/2022 - present | Gurgaon, India

Software Developer,

Amdocs Development Center India LLP 05/2021 - 11/2021 | Gurgaon, India

Software Engineer, Cavisson Systems Inc. 11/2019 - 05/2021 | Noida, India

Associate Software Engineer, Cavisson Systems Inc 03/2019 - 11/2019 | Noida, India

Certificates

Semi-Finalist

Tech Gig Code Gladiators 2021 - Organized by Cognizant

Certificate of Appreciation

Online Cafeteria, NIC, India

Profile

Diligent software engineer with 3+ years of experience application commercial and development. In previous roles, slashed downtime by 25% and ensured 98% on-time project completion. Also identified and dealt with a significant process bottleneck that boosted coding efficiency by 35% when resolved.

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE (C/C++), **SCRIPTING LANGUAGE** (SHELL/BASH, BATCH), **OPERATING SYSTEMS (UNIX/LINUX (UBUNTU),** WINDOWS),

CODE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (GIT, BIT BUCKET), SYSTEM DESIGN (HLD, LLD), **OTHERS** (DATA STRUCTURES & ALGORITHMS, OOPS)

TRAINings

National Informatics Centre, Govt of India

06/2018 - 07/2018 | Delhi, India

The Online Cafeteria Management System is an online System in which Students can book their meals from the android application, and Admin can create and edit the food Menu.

Projects

Ensemble, Amdocs Development Center

05/2021 - present

Ensemble is Amdocs platform that provides one of the leading customer care, billing and order management solutions for convergent telecom operations.

NetHavoc, Cavisson Systems

03/2019 - 05/2021

NetHavoc breaks the application infrastructure on purpose to create Chaos in a controlled environment.